Now that we've discussed how to build a histogram,
الآن وقد ناقشنا كيفية بناء مدرج تكراري،
we can use this to determine the shape associated with our data.
يمكننا استخدام ذلك في تحديد الشكل المرتبط ببياناتنا.
Here we have three histograms,
لدينا هنا ثلاث مدرجات تكرارية
showing the shape for three different data sets.
تظهِر شكل ثلاث مجموعات مختلفة من البيانات.
The histogram that has shorter bins on the left and taller bins on the right,
المدرج التكراري الذي يتضمن السلال الأقصر إلى اليسار والسلال الأطول إلى اليمين
is considered a left skewed shape.
يُعتبر شكلًا منحرفًا إلى اليسار،
This histogram that has shorter bins on the right and taller bins on the left,
وهذا المدرج التكراري الذي يتضمن السلال الأقصر إلى اليمين والسلال الأطول إلى اليسار
is considered a right skewed shape.
يُعتبر شكلًا منحرفًا إلى اليمين.
Any distribution where you can draw a line down the middle and
وأي توزيع يمكنكم أن ترسموا فيه سطرًا أسفل المنتصف،
the right side mirrors the left side is considered symmetric.
ويعكس فيه الجانب الأيمن الجانب الأيسر، يُعتبر متماثلًا.
One of the most common symmetric distributions,
يُعرف أحد أكثر التوزيعات المتماثلة شيوعًا
is known as a normal distribution and it's also called the Bell Curve.
كتوزيع عادي، ويُسمى أيضًا "منحنى الجرس".
The shape of the distribution can actually tell us
يمكن لشكل التوزيع أن يخبرنا الكثير
a lot about the measures of center and spread.
فيما يتعلق بقياسات المنتصف والانتشار.
Symmetric distributions, like this one have a mean that's equal to the median,
التوزيعات المتماثلة، مثل هذا التوزيع، تتضمن عددًا متوسطًا مساويًا لمتوسط العدد
which also equals the mode.
الذي يساوي الوضع أيضًا.
Each of these measures sits here in the center.
يقع كلٌ من هذه التوزيعات في المنتصف.
The mode is essentially the tallest bar in our histogram.
الوضع هو بالأساس الشريط الأطول في مدرجنا التكراري.
When we have skewed distributions,
حين توجد لدينا توزيعات منحرفة
it's the case of the mean is pulled by the tail of the distribution,
فهذه هي الحالة التي يتم سحب العدد المتوسط فيها عن طريق ذيل التوزيع،
while the median stays closer to the mode.
بينما يظل متوسط العدد أقرب إلى الوضع.
For example, in this right skewed distribution,
مثلًا، في هذا المنحنى المنحرف إلى اليمين
the mean would be pulled higher,
سيتم سحب العدد المتوسط إلى الأعلى،
resulting in a mean that's greater than our median.
مما ينتِج عددًا متوسطًا أكبر من متوسط العدد الخاص بنا.
Alternatively, in a left skewed distribution,
بدلًا من ذلك، في التوزيع المنحرف إلى اليسار
our mean is pulled down here,
يتم سحب العدد المتوسط خاصتنا إلى الأسفل هنا،
resulting in a mean that's less than our median.
مما ينتِج عددًا متوسطًا أقل من متوسط العدد الخاص بنا.
In order to relate this to the visual of a histogram,
لكي نربط هذا بالجانب المرئي للمدرج التكراري،
back to the five number summary we saw on the earlier lessons,
وبالعودة إلى ملخص الأرقام الخمسة الذي رأيناه في الدروس السابقة،
here are the corresponding box plots below each histogram.
ها هي مخططات المربع المتوافق أسفل كل مدرج تكراري.
Notice how the whiskers stretch in the direction of the skew,
لاحِظوا كيف تتوسَّع الخطوط في اتجاه الانحراف
for each of the skewed distributions.
في كلٍ من التوزيعات المنحرفة،
That is the longer whisker is on the left,
حتى يصبح الخط الأطول إلى اليسار
for a left skewed distribution and it's on the right,
في التوزيع المنحرف إلى اليسار، ويصبح إلى اليمين
for the right skewed distribution.
في التوزيع المنحرف إلى اليمين.
Alternatively, the symmetric histogram also has a symmetric box spot.
بدلًا من ذلك، يتضمن المدرج التكراري المتماثل نقطة مربع متماثلة أيضًا.